Finding aid for John Duke papers CA.MS.00066
Smith College Archives
John Duke papers
1913-1984
Smith College Archives
Duke, John Woods
CA.MS.00066
51.958 linear feet (49 containers)
John Duke was a professor of music at Smith College and a distinguished composer and pianist, best known for his art-songs in English. This collection contains scores, correspondence with numerous internationally known musicians and others, scrapbooks, writings, recordings, printed materials, and miscellaneous papers.
Biographical / Historical
John Duke was a distinguished composer, pianist, and teacher of piano. He is best known for his art-songs in English, which were composed between 1920 and his death in 1984. His works also include solo instrumental pieces, instrumental and vocal chamber music, choral and symphonic works, and music for the stage. He composed two operas ("Captain Lovelock," 1953; "The Sire de Maletroit," 1958), an operetta ("The Yankee Pedlar," 1962), a "musical fantasy for children" ("The Cat That Walked Himself": 1964), and music for numerous Smith College faculty shows and theatre department productions.
John Duke was born in Cumberland, Maryland, on July 30, 1899. He became interested in music through his mother, Matilda Hoffman Duke. "A music lover and a talented singer," she was Duke's first music teacher. At age 16 he won a three-year scholarship to the Peabody Conservatory of Music in Baltimore. There he studied piano with Harold Randolph and theory and composition with Gustav Strube.
In 1918, following a period of volunteer service in the Army, Duke continued his music study in New York City with lessons in piano from Franklin Cannon and in composition from Howard Brockway and Bernard Wagenaar. In 1920 he made his New York piano debut in Aeolian Hall.
On December 22, 1922, he married Dorothy Macon, a writer. The couple often collaborated on musical works and on lecture-recitals. Dorothy Duke wrote the libretto for "The Sire de Meletroit," "The Yankee Pedlar," and "The Cat That Walked by Himself," as well as texts for several Smith College faculty shows.
In 1922 and 1923 Duke was editor of the American Piano Company Recording Labs. He made recordings for them and for the Duo-Art Company. His compositions were first published in 1923, when G. Schirmer, Inc., printed his first two songs, "I've Dreamed of Sunsets" and "Lullaby."
Duke's long affiliation with Smith College began in the fall of 1923, when he was appointed assistant professor of music. Duke taught piano and in the 1950s and 1960s offered a course in the literature of the piano. In 1938 he was made a full professor of music, a position he held until he was honored with the Henry Dike Sleeper Chair in 1960.
Duke was an active performer and lecturer throughout the Connecticut River Valley (and beyond), giving many recitals and lecture-recitals and teaching a number of University Extension Service of the Connecticut Valley courses, mainly in piano literature and pedagogy. He also wrote columns and reviewed concerts for the Daily Hampshire Gazette.
Duke spent his first sabbatical from Smith (1929-1930) studying in Europe with Nadia Boulanger and Artur Schnabel. He was a member of the Yaddo Summer Music Colony in Saratoga Springs, New York, in 1936 and 1937, and he served as program chair for the Yaddo concert series of contemporary American chamber music in 1937. In 1941 Duke's "Carnival Overture" was given its premiere by the Boston Pops Orchestra. His 1944 sabbatical was spent in New York City, where he was chair of the National Association of American Composers and Conductors and arranged a series of four concerts of contemporary chamber music.
Duke's association with John Seagle and the Seagle Colony, the summer school for singers in Schroon Lake, New York, began in 1951, when his daughter Karen attended a session. From then until his death, Mr. Duke almost always made an annual visit to the colony. His operas, "Captain Lovelock" and "The Sire de Maletroit," were written for the Opera Guild at the colony and were first performed there. Duke wrote other pieces for the colony (e.g., "Lord, Bless This Food") and was often present for workshops or performances of his music.
John Duke was honored by this hometown of Cumberland, Maryland, when April 1, 1957, was declared "John Duke Day." Other honors included the American Society of Composers and Publishers Standard Award to composers, which he received for twenty-two consecutive years (1963-84). The Peabody Conservatory Alumni Association bestowed on him its Award for Distinguished Service in 1969.
John Duke retired from Smith College as professor emeritus in 1967. He remained active as a composer, writing 126 of his 265 catalogued songs after that time. He died in Northampton on October 26, 1984.
Scope and Contents
The John Duke papers include scores, correspondence, scrapbooks, writings, recordings, printed materials and miscellaneous papers which document Duke's life and career. They are concentrated in the years following his appointment to the faculty of Smith College in 1923. There is very little from his youth and student days.
The scores of John Duke's compositions make up the most important portion of the papers. Included are copies of all of the 265 catalogued songs which constitute Duke's major output as a composer. All known mature Duke works are available in manuscript and/or final form. There are also a few scores of student works and some unfinished works, including the song he was composing at the time of his death.
There is good material for the study of John Duke's method and philosophy of composition. Manuscript notebooks include rhythmic, melodic, and harmonic sketches of a number of the works composed between 1944 and 1984. Duke's lectures and writings on the art-song, the drafts of outgoing correspondence, and letters from poets such as Archibald MacLeish, William Rose Benet, Mark Van Doren, and Richard Nickson give a clear picture of Duke's thinking about the musical form he loved best and about this choice of texts to set.
Duke's triple career (composer, teacher, pianist) is well documented. His career as a composer can be traced not only through the material above but also through correspondence from colleagues, friends, family, singers, and other musicians. Included are such prominent contemporaries as Roger Sessions, Aaron Copland, Walter Piston, Wayne Barlow, Sigmund Spaeth, Daniel Gregory Mason, Mack Harrell, Gladys Swarthout, Ross Lee Finney, Roy Harris, Arthur Fieldler, William Warfield, and Douglas Moore.
Correspondence from Duke's piano students attests to his lasting influence as a teacher. His devotion to teaching and to the problems of pedagogy is in evidence in that correspondence and in the texts of his lectures and writings on piano technique and literature.
Duke's career as a pianist is documented in correspondence from teachers, impresarios, piano companies, and supportive friends. The letters received before 1945, when he began to devote his time more exclusively to composing, clearly reflect the problems of an artist getting started. Duke's continued activity as a performing musician is well documented by scrapbooks and concert programs.
This finding aid has four appendices.
Appendix I: Catalogue of songs by John Duke - by song number
Appendix II: Catalogue of songs by John Duke - alphabetical by title
Appendix III: Catalogue of songs by John Duke - alphabetical by poet
Appendix IV: Bibliography of compositions by John Duke
Arrangement
This collection is organized into six series:
Series I. Scores, 1921-1984, n.d.
Series II. Biographical and Personal Material, 1922-1984, n.d.
Series III. Correspondence, 1913-1984.
Series IV. Professional Activities, 1916-1984.
Series V. Speaking and Writing, 1920-1984.
Series VI. Recordings, 1939-1984.
Related Material
John Duke Library Guide, Smith College
22. Friends of The Smith College Library Oral History Project
40.Out But Not Down Club
52.Department of Music Records
Conditions Governing Access
The papers are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The John Duke Papers came to the Smith College Archives in January 1985. The scores were a bequest of John Duke, and the remaining materials were a gift of his daughter, Karen Duke Sturges.
Composition (Music)--History--20th century--Sources; Smith College--Faculty
- Series I. SCORES, 1921-1984; undated
  Scope and Contents of the Collection
  This series is divided into four sections: Manuscript Scores; Transparencies; File Copies; and Scripts and Texts. Unless otherwise noted the scores are arranged within the sections in the following six categories designated by John Duke: Songs, Choral Works, Symphonic Works, Dramatic Works, Solo Pieces and Chamber Music, and Miscellaneous. Uncatalogued and unnumbered songs are pieces for solo voice and piano or organ which John Duke did not include in his Catalogue of Songs (Appendix I). The first section, Manuscript Scores, consists of penciled copies of Duke's compositions. Manuscript notebooks (1944-1984) are filed chronologically in the first three boxes. Unbound manuscript scores follow in boxes 4-7, arranged in Duke's six categories. There are manuscript versions of all but 13 of John Duke's 265 catalogued songs, most of his other works, and a few student compositions. John Duke made final copies of scores on Transparencies for purposes of reproduction. Included are all but 7 of his catalogued songs and many of his other works. File Copies are printed, mimeographed, or photocopied scores which contain corrections, fingerings, or performance notes in John Duke's hand. These copies were part of John Duke's file of scores to be used for performances and loans. Included are many of Duke's catalogued songs and most of his other works. Scripts and Texts consists of typescript, mimeograph, or photocopy versions of the libretti of two of Duke's dramatic works, "The Cat That Walked By Himself" and "The Yankee Pedlar," plus a number of texts for Smith College faculty shows.
  - Manuscript Scores
    - First compositions: notebook, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - First compositions: "Meditation," "Etude," and "Mazurka" for piano, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript Notebooks
      - "The Cat That Walked By Himself", 1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Songs no. 71-76, 264; Sketches for "Captain Lovelock", 1951- 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - "Captain Lovelock"
        - Rhythmic Sketches, 1952-53 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Scenes I-IV, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Scene V, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Songs with sketches no. 90-95;, "The Sire de Maletroit", 1957-59 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - "The Sire de Maletroit", 1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Songs no. 95-100; "The Way, The Truth, The Life for voice and organ"; "I Love The Lord" for voice and piano; Sketches for "The Yankee Pedlar", 1959- 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Music for "Love Rides the Rails," Smith College Faculty Show; "Gretchen am Spinnrade" for voice and piano, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Songs no. 101, 103, 104, 111; "Three River Songs" for 3-part women's chorus and piano; "Ezra's Song" from "Yankee Pedlar", 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - "The Yankee Pedlar": ms. and sketches, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - "The Yankee Pedlar": ms. and sketches, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Songs no. 110, 112-120, 122, 123, 1964-65 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Songs no. 124-131; Sketch, untitled (1965 Jun), 1965-67 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Songs no. 133-141; "Ulysses Speaks": unfinished song, 1967-68; undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Songs no. 105-109, 132, 142, 143; "The Yankee Pedlar": overture, 1962; 1967-68 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Songs no. 144-152, 1968-69 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Songs no. 158-168, 1970-71 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Songs with sketches no. 153-157, 176, 1970; 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Songs no. 169-175, 183, 184, 191; "Ave Gertrudia Smithiensis" for 4-part chorus (1971 May 11); "Twang the Lyre" for 4-part women's chorus; Sketches, miscellaneous, 1971-72; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Songs with sketches no. 178, 180-182, 185-190; "Psalm 23" version for mixed chorus; "A Round for Robert" (1973 Dec 28), 1972-74 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Songs with sketches no. 179, 180, 192, 193, 205; "A Christmas Hymn," choral and solo versions; Sketches, miscellaneous, 1972-76; undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Songs no. 194-202, 208, 1975-77 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Songs no. 203-207, 209-212, 1976-79 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Songs no. 213-225, 1979-81 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Songs with sketches no. 93, 226-236, 1959; 1981 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Songs no. 237-250; Sketch, "The Revellers", 1982-83; undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Songs no. 251 -265; Sketches, miscellaneous, 1983-84 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Songs, Catalogued
      - no. 1, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - no. 3-11, 1924-35 (Box 4, Folder 32-39)
      - no. 17-24, 1935-39 (Box 4, Folder 40-46)
      - no. 26-31, 1940-45 (Box 4, Folder 47-52)
      - no. 33-42, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 53-62)
      - no. 44-55, 1946-48 (Box 4, Folder 63-74)
      - no. 56-58, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 75-77)
      - no. 60-70, 1949-51 (Box 5, Folder 78-88)
      - no. 74-87, 1952-56 (Box 5, Folder 89-102)
      - no. 98-99, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 103-104)
      - no. 102, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Songs, Uncatalogued
      - no. 177, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 106)
      - "Two Songs for Soprano", 1917 (Box 5, Folder 107)
      - "A Dirge" (Percy Bysshe Shelley), undated (Box 5, Folder 108)
      - "Arab Love Song" (Francis Thompson), undated (Box 5, Folder 109)
      - "Bad", undated (Box 5, Folder 110)
      - "Moon Song" (Jessica Jackson), undated (Box 5, Folder 111)
      - "Music, When Soft Voices Die" (Percy Bysshe Shelley), undated (Box 5, Folder 112)
      - "Oh, John!" arrangement by John Duke, undated (Box 5, Folder 113)
      - "Softly, Softly the Snow Drifts Down" (Caroline Neilson), 1928 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Choral Works
      - ""Magnificat" for organ and unison chorus, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      - "Psalm 23" for women's chorus, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Symphonic Works
      - "The Fairy Glen" for flute, harp, and strings, undated (Box 6, Folder 117)
      - "Dance in A-major" for string orchestra: score and parts, undated (Box 6, Folder 118-123)
      - "Carnival Overturen, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 124)
      - "Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra", 1938 (Box 6, Folder 125-127)
    - Dramatic Works
      - "The Cat That Walked by Himself", 1944 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Solo Pieces and Chamber Music
      - "March Humoreske" (sic) for piano, undated (Box 7, Folder 129)
      - "A Valentine" for piano, undated (Box 7, Folder 130)
      - "Souvenir" for piano, 1928 Dec 23 (Box 7, Folder 131)
      - "Two Pieces for Violoncello Alone", undated (Box 7, Folder 132)
      - "Two Sketches for Violoncello Alone", 1934 (Box 7, Folder 133)
      - "Air in F-major" for violin and piano, undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
      - "Narrative" for viola and piano, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 135)
      - "Dialogue" for cello and piano, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 136)
      - "Melody in E-flat major" for cello and piano, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 137)
      - "Trio in D-major" for violin, cello, and piano: score and parts, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 138)
      - "Trio in G-major" for violin, viola, and cello, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 139)
      - "String Quartet Number 2", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cadenzas for "Piano Concerto in G-major" by Ludwig van Beethoven, 1934 Aug (Box 7, Folder 141-142)
    - "Gretchen am I.B.M." for voice and piano, undated (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - "Lord Bless This Food" for 4-part chorus, undated (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Incidental music for "Androcles and the Lion," a marionette play staged by Oliver Larkin, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Loan lib songs I (Box 46)
    - Loan lib songs II (Box 47)
    - Three loan choral and symphony I (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous music librettos and other materials (Box 49)
    - Music for Smith College Faculty Shows
      - "A Day on the Campus" for miscellaneous percussion: score and parts, 1949 May 19 (Box 7, Folder 146)
      - "Dear Old Thmith", 1952 (Box 7, Folder 147)
      - "Simon Darkway's Song", 1960 (Box 7, Folder 148)
      - "Timpanic (sic) Poem" for percussion orchestra: score and parts, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 149)
  - Transparencies
    - Songs, Catalogued
      - no. 2, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - no. 7-49, 1928-47 (Box 8, Folder 151-193)
      - no. 50-109, 1947-62 (Box 9, Folder 194-241)
      - no. 110-126, 1964-66 (Box 10, Folder 242-253a)
      - no. 128-179, 1966-72 (Box 10, Folder 254-289)
      - no. 180-192, 1972-74 (Box 11, Folder 290-297)
      - no. 194-239, 1975-82 (Box 11, Folder 298-338)
      - no. 240-265, 1982-84 (Box 11, Folder 339-364)
    - Songs, Uncatalogued
      - "A Christmas Hyman (Richard Wilbur), version for solo voice and piano, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 365)
      - "I Love the Lord" for voice and piano, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 366)
    - Choral Works
      - "Psalm 23n for women's choir, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 367)
      - "O, Sing Unto the Lord a New Song" for 3-part women's chorus and organ: full score and vocal score, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 368-369)
      - "Love Unconquerable" for 4-part women's chorus, undated (Box 12, Folder 370)
      - "Three River Songs" for 3-part women's chorus and piano, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 371)
      - "Magnificat" for solo voice or unison chorus, and organ, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 372)
    - Orchestral Works
      - "Carnival Overturen: parts, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 373-375)
      - "Concerto for Piano and Strings" (unrevised): score and parts, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 376-377)
    - Dramatic Works
      - "The Cat That Walked by Himself": score, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 378)
      - "The Sire de Maletroit", 1957 Dec (Box 13, Folder 379)
    - Solo Pieces and Chamber Music
      - "Rondo in B-major" for piano, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 380)
      - "Souvenir" for piano, 1928 Dec 23 (Box 13, Folder 381)
      - "Suite for Viola Alone", 1933 (Box 13, Folder 382)
      - "Fantasy" for violin and piano: score and part, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 383)
      - "Narrative" for viola and piano: score and part, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 384)
      - "Dialogue" for cello and piano: score and part, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 385)
      - "Melody in E-flat major" for cello and piano: score and part, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 386)
      - "Trio in D-major" for violin, cello, and piano: score and parts, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 387-388)
      - "Trio in G-major" for violin, viola, and piano: score and parts, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 389-390)
      - "String Quartet Number 1": score and parts, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 391-395)
      - "String Quartet Number 2": score and parts, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 396-400)
  - File Copies
    - Songs, Catalogued
      - no. 1-7, 1920-28 (Box 14, Folder 401-407)
      - no. 9-10, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 408-409)
      - no. 12-24, 1935-40 (Box 14, Folder 410-419)
      - no. 26, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 420)
      - no. 28-33, 1945-46 (Box 14, Folder 421-426)
      - no. 35-38, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 427-429)
        General
        (no. 36 missing 10/11/01)
      - no. 43-44, 1946-47 (Box 14, Folder 430-431)
      - no. 46-49, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 432-436)
      - no. 51-52, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 437-438)
      - no. 54, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 439)
      - no. 56, 1948 (Box 14, Folder 440)
      - no. 58-60, 1948-49 (Box 14, Folder 441-443)
      - no. 61-65, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 444)
      - no. 67-69, 1950-51 (Box 15, Folder 445-447)
      - no. 71-76, 1951-52 (Box 15, Folder 448-453)
      - no. 78-79, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 454-455)
      - no. 81-84, 1954-55 (Box 15, Folder 456-459)
      - no. 86, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 460)
      - no. 89, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 461)
      - no. 91-93, 1958-59 (Box 15, Folder 462-464)
      - no. 95-100, 1959-60 (Box 15, Folder 465-468)
      - no. 102, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 469-470)
      - no. 104-109, 1961-62 (Box 15, Folder 471-472)
      - no. 110-113, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 473-476)
      - no. 117-141, 1965-68 (Box 16, Folder 471-491)
      - no. 143-162, 1968-70 (Box 16, Folder 492-500)
      - no. 165, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 501)
      - no. 166-176, 1971-72 (Box 17, Folder 502-508)
      - no. 180-191, 1972-74 (Box 17, Folder 509-515)
      - no. 193-197, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 516-517)
      - no. 200, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 518)
      - no. 205, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 519)
      - no. 207, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 520)
      - no. 209, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 521)
      - no. 211-212, 1978-79 (Box 17, Folder 522-523)
      - no. 215, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 524)
      - no. 217-219, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 525)
      - no. 222-223, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 526-527)
      - no. 228, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 528)
      - no. 230-232, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 529-531)
      - no. 235, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 532)
      - no. 237-241, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 532a)
      - no. 237-239, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 533-535)
      - no. 240-242, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 536-538)
      - no. 244, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 539)
      - no. 246, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 540)
      - no. 251-252, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 541-542)
      - no. 257, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 543)
    - Songs, Uncatalogued
      - "Bread and Music" (Conrad Aiken), 1950 (Box 18, Folder 544)
      - "A Christmas Hymn" (Richard Wilbur), version for solo voice and piano, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 545)
      - "A Dirge" (Percy Bysshe Shelley), undated (Box 18, Folder 546)
      - "The Way, The Truth, The Life" for voice and organ, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 547)
    - Choral Works
      - "A Christmas Hymn" (Richard Wilbur) for mixed chorus, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 548)
      - "A Grace Before Singing" for 4-part women's chorus, undated (Box 18, Folder 549)
      - "The Cloud" (Sara Teasdale) for 3-part chorus and piano: piano part only, undated (Box 18, Folder 550)
      - "Love Unconquerable" for women's chorus, undated (Box 18, Folder 551)
      - "Magnificat" for solo voice or unison chorus and organ, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 552)
      - "O, Sing Unto the Lord a New Song" for 3-part women's chorus and string orchestra: full score, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 553)
      - "Pole Star for This Year" (Archibald MacLeish) for a capella 4-part chorus, undated (Box 18, Folder 554)
      - "Psalm 23," version for mixed chorus; "Three River Songs" for women's chorus and piano, 1963; 1974 (Box 18, Folder 555)
      - "When Slim Sophia Mounts Her Horse" (Walter de la Mare), version for 3-part women's chorus and piano, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 556)
    - Symphonic Works
      - "Concerto for Piano and String Orchestra": revised score and parts, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 557-562)
      - "Overture in D-minor for String Orchestra": score and parts, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 563-567)
    - Dramatic Works
      - "Captain Lovelock", 1953 (Box 20, Folder 568)
      - "The Sire de Maletroit", 1957 (Box 20, Folder 569)
      - "The Yankee Pedlar"
        - Score, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 570)
        - Overture for piano, 4 hands, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 571)
    - Solo Pieces and Chamber Music
      - "The Fairy Glen" for piano, 1922 (Box 21, Folder 572)
      - "March Humoreske" (sic) for piano, undated (Box 21, Folder 573)
      - "Rondo" for piano, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 574)
      - "Suite for Viola Alone", 1933 (Box 21, Folder 575)
      - "Fantasy" for violin and piano, 1936 (Box 21, Folder 576)
      - "Melody in E-flat" for viola and piano, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 577)
      - "Narrative" for viola and piano, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 578)
    - Miscellaneous
      - "A Round for Robert", 1973 (Box 21, Folder 579)
      - "Ave Gertrudia Smithiensis", 1971 (Box 21, Folder 580)
      - "Northampton Hymn," for Northampton's tercentary, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 581)
      - "The Good Old Days," for Smith College Faculty Show, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 582)